

Valentino Urbano

Via Volta 10 – Rho (MI) – Italy Ul. Fitelberga 5 – Bytom - Polanc

(+39) 3389923193

valentino@valentinourbano.com http://valentinourbano.com

Github | LinkedIn | Twitter

Skills

iOS Dev:

Objective-C, Swift, Cordova, Unity, Xcode, Appcode, Cocoa, Cocoa Touch, SQLite, GCD, AVFoundation, MapKit, Navigation, AR, Realm, OAuth 2, Cryptography, Certificate Pinning, Animations, MapKit, REST, JSON, XML, SOAP, Unit Testing, Ul Testing, Continous Integration, Fastlane, Cocoapods, Carthage, Swift Package Manager

Android: Android Studio

WebDev (Frontend):

HTML 5, CSS3, Javascript, PHP, Word press

WebDev (Backend):

LAMP, Magento, Magento REST, phpmyadmin, SQL, SSL, Jekyll, MySQL, MongoDB

DevOps:

SSH, SSH Keys, FTP, VPN, Bash, Linux (Debian, CentOS, Linux Lite, Fedora, Ubuntu), NAS, Network configuration, HDD recovery

Source Control: Git, Git Flow, SVN

Design:

Adobe XD, Sketch, Gimp, ImageMagick

Pandoras:

Integrating Pandora's box (mapping)

Miscellaneous

Word, Excel, Google Docs, Python Java.C#.Rubv.Unitv.

Summary

Gender Male | Day of Birth 22/08/1993 | Nationality Italian

I work developing apps for iOS, web applications (mainly backend and databases) and in DevOps. I've been writing online since 2007 and I have had a website since 2009. I currently write on my Blog. I also work on some personal projects, write and play guitar.

Work history

January 2016 – March 2018

Lead Developer

3Wlab SRL, Roma

- Development, analysis, deployment and support of a system (software/hardware) for Volkswagen Italia to revolutionize the sale process inside and outside the dealerships.
- Development, analysis and deployment of a Digital Shopping Experience for Moncler.
- Development and support of a banking application for Banca Intesa which won the "Best Finance Application of 2017" and "Best Finance Application of 2018" awards.
- Development of 6 applications for Italian and International partners in different areas of business, from medical to tourism.

September 2014 – December 2015

Freelancer

Remote, Poland

 Development of around 15 iPhone/Mac applications as personal projects as well as freelance contracts for various businesses.

Education

September 2012 – November 2014

September 2007 – July 2012 Computer Science

Università Statale di Milano, Italy

Aeronautical Expert Diploma ISS JC Maxwell, Milano

Competencies

Languages

Italian, English (CAE Certificate), Polish

Driving License

B, International

Other information

Extensive experience working remotely in a distributed team, strong self-learning skills. defined projects architecture and scope with final client, managed multiple development teams.